charmtracker.com 2017-04-25

# Privacy Policy

### General

MedicalMine Inc., is a Pleasanton, California based company and maker of popular ChARM suite of products, built to address application of cloud and mobile technologies for managing healthcare data and intelligent data analysis. ChARM product suite includes Integrated EHR, Practice Management and RCM solution, Patient Portal for Patient Engagement, TeleHealth solution for Remote patient care, Connect solution for Collaborative communication, along with a slew of Mobile apps across platforms. 

At MedicalMine, we respect your need for online privacy and protect any Personal Information that you may share with us, in an appropriate manner. MedicalMine's servers and infrastructure are hosted at Tier 3 Plus data centers equipped with latest technology to securely house sensitive data. We have put in place elaborate security processes to ensure utmost security and privacy of health care information. MedicalMine follows very strict and standardized practices in areas of Access Controls, Network Security, Physical Security, Information Security, Application Security, Operations Security and Business Continuity. In addition, all communications between users' browser and MedicalMine applications are encrypted using Secure Socket Layer (SSL). ​ 

### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield

MedicalMine Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. MedicalMine Inc. has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, MedicalMine Inc. commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact MedicalMine Inc. at [legal@medicalmine.com](mailto:legal@medicalmine.com)

MedicalMine Inc. has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to Better Business Bureau ([www.bbb.org](https://www.bbb.org/)), an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit <https://www.bbb.org/greater-san-francisco/business-reviews/health-recording-service/charm-health-in-pleasanton-ca-876694> for more information or to file a complaint. The services of Better Business Bureau (BBB) are provided at no cost to you.

### Information Recorded and Use

### Personal Information

During the Registration Process for creating a Practice or Patient account, we request your name and email address. You will also be asked to choose a unique username and a password, which will be used solely for the purpose of providing access to your user account. Your name and email address will be used to inform you regarding new services, releases, upcoming events and changes in this Privacy Policy Statement. Your personal information will not be shared with other entities without your explicit consent.

### Protected Health Information (PHI)

MedicalMine is a Business Associate as defined under the administrative simplification provisions of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 and its privacy and security regulations (HIPAA), and under the privacy and security provisions of the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act of 2009 (the HITECH Act). We will comply with the business associate provisions of these regulations with regard to Protected Health Information. We will also comply with provisions of the HIPAA Security Rule that apply to business associates under the HITECH Act, and the privacy and security provisions of the HITECH Act that are applicable to business associates. 

### Permitted Uses and Disclosure of PHI

MedicalMine permits use and disclosure of PHI in accordance with the HIPAA and HITECH, as described below: 

  * Allow access to protected health information to you and your staff for the purpose of providing healthcare.
  * Allow access to protected health information for other health care providers and their business associates for treatment. This includes disclosing health information for related applications that you select, such as clinical laboratory reporting, billing and e-prescribing, as well as to other health care providers to whom you agree to give access to patient's protected health information for treatment. You agree to be bound by the terms of use and other agreements relating to such third-party products and services.
  * Allow access to protected health information to your patients through our PHR portal. You control which of your patients have access to their health records, and what kind of information they can see.
  * Allow use of De-identified health information for research purpose
  * Create limited data sets from patient health information, and disclose them for any purpose for which you may disclose a limited data set.
  * Aggregate health information with that of other users, and use the aggregated information for reporting and share aggregated information in accordance with applicable state and federal law.

We may disclose protected health information if the disclosure is required by law. We reserve the right to make any other uses of your health information that are permitted to a Business Associate. However, except as permitted by the Privacy Rule, we will not use or disclose protected​ health information in any manner that would violate the Privacy Rule. Patient entered health information is shared by the patient with practitioners in accordance with permissions set by the patient. 

### Usage Details

Your usage details such as time, frequency, duration and pattern of use, features used and the amount of storage used will be recorded by us in order to enhance your experience of the MedicalMine services and to help us provide you the best possible service. 

### Contents in your User Account

We store and maintain files, documents, task lists, messages and other data stored in your user account at our facilities in the United States. In order to prevent loss of data due to errors or system failures, we also keep backup copies of data including the contents of your user account. Hence, your files and data may remain on our servers even after deletion or termination of your user account. We assure you that the contents of your user account will not be disclosed to anyone and will not be accessible even to employees of MedicalMine except in circumstances specifically mentioned in this Privacy Policy Statement and Terms of Services. We also do not process the contents of your user account for serving targeted advertisements. 

### Financial Information

In case of services requiring payment, we request credit card or other payment account information, which will be used solely for processing payments. Your financial information will not be stored by us except for the name and address of the card holder, the expiry date and the last four digits of the Credit Card number. Subject to your prior consent and where necessary for processing future payments, your financial information will be stored in encrypted form on secure servers of our reputed Payment Gateway Service Provider who is beholden to treating your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy Statement. 

### Visitor Details

We use the Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, referring URL, files accessed, errors generated, time zone, operating system and other visitor details collected in our log files to analyze the trends, administer the website, track visitor's movements and to improve our website. 

###  Cookies

We use temporary and permanent cookies to enhance your experience of our site.Temporary cookies will be removed from your computer each time you close your browser.Permanent cookies remain on your hard drive after you've exited from our site, until you erase them or they expire. Permanent cookies will not contain any personal information about you. If you have turned cookies off, you may not be able to use access controlled areas of the website. We tie cookie information to your email address when you elect to remain logged in so as to maintain and recall your preferences within the website. We may from time to time employ the use of pixel tags on the website and in emails. Pixel tags such as web beacons are 1x1 images that are embedded onto a web page to document traffic and for website analytics without collecting any Personal Information. 

### Notification of Changes

Any changes to the Privacy Policy Statement will be posted on our website in order to keep you informed of any changes in nature of information collected, manner of collection, use and sharing of information. If at any point we decide to use Personal Information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you by email and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. You will not receive email notification of minor changes to the Privacy Policy Statement. If you are concerned about how your Personal Information is used, you should check back at our website periodically. 

### General Medical Information and User Forums

The general medical information made available on our web site or by the application is for informational and educational purpose only and does not constitute medical advice. Any health related questions you may have about the treatments should be discussed with your medical provider. Medical Mine Incorporated is not responsible for any medical advice provided by its employees or by the participants in the supported forums. Such forums are created for discussion and support between fellow caregivers and patients and not intended to provide advice about treatments. 

### Password protection

Access to our applications is password protected. We strongly recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone and that you update your credentials on a regular basis. Exercise the utmost personal security in how you handle your password. MedicalMine will never ask for your password in an unsolicited phone call or unsolicited email. 

### Emails

Your email address is never used for any purpose other than to communicate with you or on your behalf. Your email may also be used for forgotten password or user account information. We will not use your email address to send you any promotional and marketing materials. MedicalMine never shares your email address with external entities.​ 

### Links from our website

Some pages of our website contain external links. You are advised to verify the privacy practices of such other websites. We are not responsible for the manner of use or misuse of information made available by you at such other websites. We encourage you not to provide Personal Information, without assuring yourselves of the Privacy Policy Statement of other websites. 

### Investigation of Illegal Activity

We may need to provide access to your Personal Information and the contents of your user account to our employees and service providers for the purpose of investigating any suspected illegal activity or potential violation of the terms and conditions for use of MedicalMine applications. However, MedicalMine will ensure that such access is in compliance with this Privacy Policy Statement and subject to appropriate confidentiality and security measures. 

### Children's Online Privacy Protection

We have no intention of accepting any information from individuals under the age of 18. If you are not yet 18 years of age, please leave this site immediately.Parents are urged to monitor and supervise their children’s on-line activity. 

### Questions & Concerns

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy Statement, please contact us at legal@medicalmine.com. We shall respond to all inquiries within 30 days of receipt upon ascertaining your identity.
